JOSÉ MARIA CANUTO B. GASTON

t: +1(609)901-0642 e: jmcbgaston@gmail.com Oakland, CA Linkedin GitHub

Collaborative Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience. A self-starter with an eye for design and a product mindset. Recently laid off and currently seeking full-time roles in a remote environment.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, Ruby, Angular, Svelte, SvelteKit, React, Elf, Redux, HTML, CSS, Sass, Tailwind, Jest, Vitest, Ruby on Rails, Swagger, Rspec, PostgreSQL, AWS, Git, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Engineer | Flow | October-2021 - November 2023 | Hybrid

- Led the successful adoption of the SvelteKit framework and Vitest testing library onto a new fully operational application in a matter of 4 months. This solution is now used by 90% of our current users and enhances overall user experience by being fully mobile-friendly.
- Mastered Angular and RxJs within a short timeframe, surpassing initial expertise in React.
- Orchestrated seamless collaboration across cross-functional teams, aligning technical solutions with the vision of design and product teams.
- Drove a product and design-focused approach, actively contributing insights to align technical implementations with user needs and project objectives.
- Facilitated collaborative knowledge transfer sessions through pair programming, expediting the
 onboarding of new team members and fostering a unified understanding of best practices within
 the team.
- Actively contributed to retrospective meetings, fostering a culture of continuous improvement that directly contributed to the team's success.
- Innovated and implemented best practices, resulting in the continual refinement and structuring of tickets for enhanced workflow efficiency.
- Authored comprehensive technical documentation, empowering the team with clear direction and ensuring the success of upcoming projects.

Frontend Developer | breathing.ai | April-2021 - October 2021 | Remote

- Developed a scalable React front end based on high-fidelity Figma mock-ups, resulting in a seamless and user-friendly interface for customer onboarding.
- Collaborated closely with the design team to refine interactability and design details, contributing to a successful go-live and enhancing the overall user experience.

EDUCATION

App Academy | July 2020 - November 2020 | San Francisco, CA | Remote 1000+ hours remote experience at 16-week full-stack coding bootcamp with a < 5% acceptance rate.

University of San Francisco | August 2012 - May2016 | San Francisco, CA School of Business, Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration; GPA 3.3